<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Structure on DSF</title>
    <link>/structure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Structure on DSF</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 13:13:12 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/structure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Structural insights into differences in G protein activation by family A and family B GPCRs</title>
      <link>/structure/classa-and-classb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 13:13:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/structure/classa-and-classb/</guid>
      <description>A class和B class的GPCRs如何不同样激活G蛋白
heterotrimeric guanine nucleotide–binding protein (G protein) 异源三聚体鸟苷酸结合蛋白
GPCR激活hallmark： outward movement of the cytoplasmic end of transmembrane domain 6 (TM6)，opens up an intracellular cavity to accommodate the Gα subunit 在细胞质的TM6跨膜区会向外扩展，打开了一个细胞内的空腔来容纳Ga亚基。
A/B GPCRs的差别：
In family B GPCRs, TM6 shows a disruption of the helical fold and the formation of a sharp kink. This differs from the gradual bending in TM6 observed in family A GPCRs. Class B的TM6会有螺旋折叠的破坏和尖锐扭结的形成(需要更多的能量)，而class A的TM6仅仅只是逐渐弯曲。
Class B的GPCR缺少class A有的保守的结构motif，conserved structural motifs and conformational switches.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GTPase-activating proteins (GAP) accelerate the GTP hydrolysis mediated by GTPases</title>
      <link>/structure/gtp-turnover-assay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 13:13:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/structure/gtp-turnover-assay/</guid>
      <description>GTP酶激活蛋白加速GTP水解。 The GTPase cycle
G蛋白激活需要结合上GTP。GPCR激活表现出GEF活性就是一个消耗GTP的过程。 在这个过程中加入ADP，会使没有被消耗的GTP转化为ATP。这是两个竞争性结合游离磷酸的过程。然后通过将ATP的信号转换为荧光信号进行检测。 也就是说，GTP消耗的越多，剩下的ATP就越少，检测的荧光越弱，说明GPCR的活性更高。
GEFs help in loading of GDP-bound inactive GTPases(G protein) with GTP. The GEF buffer contains higher amounts of free Mg2+, and as a consequence, the nucleotide loading is catalyzed solely by GEFs.
可以检测Intrinsic GTPase 、GAP-Stimulated GTPase、GAP Activity 、GEF Activity.
GTPase/GAP Buffer: To perform a GAP activity assay, be sure to include the cognate GTPase.要进行 GAP 活性测定，请务必包含同源 GTPase。
GEF Buffer: To perform a GEF activity assay, be sure to include the cognate GTPase and GAP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>M3 Muscarinic Acetylcholine Receptors Overview</title>
      <link>/structure/m3-muscarinic-acetylcholine-receptors-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 12:00:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/structure/m3-muscarinic-acetylcholine-receptors-overview/</guid>
      <description>M3系列文章概览
   M3R的结构特征/功能作用/G蛋白偶联特异性的决定       Receptor 药用靶标 G protein     M1 神经系统疾病（如阿尔茨海默病和精神分裂症）/学习、记忆和认知 Gq/11   M2 调节人体心率和许多中枢神经系统功能 Gi/o   M3 激活后受体磷酸化，募集b抑制蛋白能力受损 / 糖耐量受损伴随着M3受体介导的胰岛胰岛素释放降低 Gq/11   M4 神经系统疾病（如阿尔茨海默病和精神分裂症） /学习、记忆和认知 Gi/o    inverse agonist, tiotropium
Positive allosteric modulators/正变构调节剂 (PAM)
SAR, structure–activity relationship
(Q)SAR 也是模型或数学关系（通常是统计相关性），它将与结构相关的特性与另一个感兴趣的特性或活动的存在或不存在或效力相关联。(Q)SAR最基本的数学形式是：
活性 = f（物理化学或结构特性）  SARs 模型的开发需要三个组件：
  为一组化学品（即因变量）提供活性（通常通过实验测量）的数据集。这组化学品通常由一些选择标准定义。因变量通常是可监测活性。
  同一组化学品的结构标准或与结构相关的特性数据集（即自变量）。自变量通常是结构属性。
  关联这两个数据数组的方法（通常是统计分析方法）。将结构与活动联系起来的方法范围从简单的线性回归，到更复杂的方法（例如偏最小二乘分析），再到最复杂的机器学习技术（例如神经网络）。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>M3-muscarinic receptor promotes insulin release via receptor phosphorylation/arrestin-dependent activation of protein kinase D1</title>
      <link>/structure/m3-help-insulin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 13:13:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/structure/m3-help-insulin/</guid>
      <description>PKD1（protein kinase C-like serine/threonine kinase）  胰岛上表达的M3-毒蕈碱受体通过受体磷酸化/抑制蛋白依赖性信号传导调节葡萄糖稳态。这个过程以蛋白激酶D1的激活为中心，该激酶在β-抑制蛋白募集到磷酸化的M3-毒蕈碱受体的下游起作用。
M3-毒蕈碱受体在激动剂占据后被一系列蛋白激酶快速磷酸化，这些蛋白激酶包括 GPCR 激酶 (GRK) 家族成员，以及酪蛋白激酶 1α 和蛋白激酶 CK2 。
受体磷酸化会调节 glucose-dependent insulin release from pancreatic islets, a response that is known to be augmented by para-sympathetic pathways （副交感神经通路）acting on M3-muscarinic receptors expressed on pancreatic β-cells。
Characterization of a Phosphorylation-Deficient Mutant M3-Muscarinic Receptor. 通过同位素[32P]orthophosphate检测磷酸化，发现磷酸化缺陷小鼠b-arrestin降低，但是不影响Gq响应Ca2+增加。
乙酰甲胆碱刺激的 [3H] 肌醇磷酸形成在M3敲除的小鼠中完全不存在。M3R-KI (Knock In)小鼠胰岛的乙酰甲胆碱刺激产生与野生型胰岛观察到的相似的反应.
M3-Muscarinic Receptor Phosphorylation Regulates Insulin Release from Isolated Pancreatic Islets. M3受体的磷酸化调控胰岛的胰岛素释放。
Disrupted Coupling of the M3-Muscarinic Receptor to PKD1 Underlies the Deficiency in Insulin Release in M3R-KI Mice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>b-arrestin overview</title>
      <link>/structure/barr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 13:13:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/structure/barr/</guid>
      <description>Abbreviations
cAMP cyclic adenosine monophosphate GPCRs G protein-coupled receptors GRK G protein-coupled receptor kinase ICL intracellular loop Nb32 nanobody 32 Nb35 nanobody 35 TM transmembrane helix V2R vasopressin receptor type 2 V2T V2R tail β2AR β2 adrenergic receptor βarr beta-arrestin 2017- Muscarinic receptor regulates extracellular signal regulated kinase by two modes of arrestin binding 毒蕈碱乙酰胆碱受体通过两种arrestin结合的方式调节细胞外信号调节激酶 Arrestin既可以在GPCR蛋白激酶磷酸化后触发脱敏和内吞作用，也可以招募和调节细胞外信号调节激酶（ERK）级联的活性。
β-arrestin 以两种不同的结合模式（瞬时和稳定）与 M1 毒蕈碱乙酰胆碱受体 (M1Rs) 结合。在任何一种结合模式下都检测到抑制蛋白中类似的分子内构象变化。
当与磷酸化 M1R 稳定结合时，β-arrestin 支架并激活 MEK 依赖性 ERK。相反，当瞬时结合时，β-arrestin 通过募集蛋白磷酸酶降低 ERK 活性。所有这些 ERK 信号都在质膜上发展。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sdAb panning</title>
      <link>/structure/functional-sdab-panning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 13:13:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/structure/functional-sdab-panning/</guid>
      <description>高通量筛选G蛋白偶联受体的功能性抗体 combining glycosylphosphatidylinositol-anchored antibody cell display with β-arrestin recruitment-based cell sorting and screening.将糖基磷脂酰肌醇锚定抗体细胞展示与基于 β-arrestin 募集的细胞分选和筛选相结合。
抗体基因型与表型；GPI 和 GPCR 在脂筏中的共定位促进了 GPI 锚定抗体与 GPCR 靶点的相互作用
免疫抗体库中鉴定出一组针对人类 apelin 受体的抗体拮抗剂和抗体激动剂来验证该方法。 相比之下，噬菌体展示仅从相同的库中获得了中性结合剂和抗体拮抗剂
sdAb GPI-anchored sdAb library (1 × 108 cells） apelin 13: 100nM 激动剂 460nm 530nm代表 产物/substrate：越低越好 1、APJ PathHunter assay 阳性clone的可溶性sdAbs有抑制剂活性
2、PathHunter β-arrestin reporter assay 不适合筛选表面抗体的细胞文库，洗完之后没有fluorescent substrate for the reporter enzyme nor the product resides in the cells
3、Tango/APJ β-arrestin assay β-内酰胺酶报告酶水解前后细胞中保留荧光底物
POC study：APJ gene is stably integrated into the genome, as well as a transcription factor linked to the C-terminus of APJ through a tobacco etch virus (TEV) protease site.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assays</title>
      <link>/structure/associate-assays/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 13:13:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/structure/associate-assays/</guid>
      <description>Bodipy-GTPγS GCGR结合GTP慢一些
a non-hydrolyzable fluorescently labeled GTP analog, which is self- quenched in solution. 不可水解的荧光标记GTP类似物
nucleotide-free receptor complexes 核苷酸free受体复合物
GCGR shows a slower Bodipy-GTPγS (kon = 0.001 s−1) binding rate compared with the β2AR (kon = 0.003s−1)，说明 efficiency of GDP release and GTP binding are significantly reduced.
Förster resonance energy transfer (FRET) GCGR结合Gs比b2慢一些
监测GPCR-Gs结合：
Cy3B-labeled GCGR (red) / Cy3B-labeled β2AR (blue) Sulfo-Cy5-labeled Gs  间发生荧光能量共振转移
G protein association rate for GCGR with an association rate constant (kon) of 0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assays Sup</title>
      <link>/structure/assays-sup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 13:13:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/structure/assays-sup/</guid>
      <description>PDB 隐藏侧链 比对结构 align ClassA_gpr75_human_Active_7BU7_2021-11-02_GPCRdb, 3sn6 and chain R（指定受体） fetch 3sn6 align ClassA_gpr75_human_Active_7BU7_2021-11-02_GPCRdb, 7rmg and chain R（匹配的不好，NK1R helix8在膜上应该是水平而非翘起） create gfp, 3WLD and resi 59-302 （分离两个部分，可以隐藏其中一个）  β2AR-Gs (pink, PDB 3SN6) peptide ligand–free state of GCGR (Fab-bound GCGR, blue, PDB 5XEZ) partial agonist NNC1702-bound GCGR (orange, PDB 5YQZ) GCGR GDP-bound Gαs (green, PDB 6EG8) Comparison between the interaction of ICL2 of GCGR (cyan) and β2AR (pink) (PDB 3SN6)
 完全激活态 ZP3780 （GCGR-Gs） 特征：</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>